# SHAHEEN AHAMMED K

# Web Developer and Graphic Designer

https://www.linkedin.com/in/shaheen-ahammed/ | https://shaheenahmd.netlify.app/https://www.behance.net/shaheenahmd | https://github.com/shaheenahmd

+971 504897626 | shaheenahmdk@gmail.com | Al Qusais, Dubai, UAE

### SUMMARY

Dedicated Web Developer with 3+ years of experience on implementing innovative web designs and user experiences. Seeking a challenging position in a reputed organization to contribute my technical skills and creativity to achieve personal and organizational goals.

## **EDUCATION**

Python Full stack Developer Internship Program | Calicut, Kerala, India 2020 - 2021

Bachelor Of Science In Mathematics with Computer Science | University Of Calicut, Kerala, India - 2019

## **SKILLS**

**Languages :** JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SCSS **Frameworks/Libraries :** React, Bootstrap, jQuery

Familiar with: Python, Django, MySQL.

Version Control: Git, GitHub

Responsive Design: Media queries, Flex-box, Grid Others: WordPress, SEO, Social Media Handling Design: Adobe Photoshop, Adobe illustrator, Figma

Soft Skills: Problem Solving, Quick learning, Team Collaboration, Time Management, Flexibility

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# WEB DEVELOPER & GRAPHIC DESIGNER | FREELANCE

Feb 2024 - Present | Dubai, United Arab Emirates

- Managed E- commerce platform of company who selling electronics products as freelancer.
- Designed visually appealing graphics and marketing materials for digital medias.
- Developed and maintained responsive websites for various clients, ensuring optimal user experience.
- Collaborated with clients to understand their business goals and translate them into functional and visually appealing websites.

September 2023 – January 2024 | Kerala, India

- Implemented responsive websites that provide optimal user experiences across all devices and screen sizes, ensuring accessibility and functionality.
- Provided graphic design services to clients, creating visually appealing and effective designs for various projects and social media ads.

# JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER | EXIMUZ TECHNOLABS

September 2021 - August 2023 | Calicut, Kerala

- Contributed to front-end development initiatives aimed at enhancing functionality and elevating user experience within interactive web applications. Leveraged expertise in HTML, JavaScirpt, Bootstrap, CSS, and jQuery to implement responsive design solutions. Additionally, collaborated on a project utilizing React.js, promoting teamwork and innovation in achieving project objectives.
- Experienced in creating userfriendly and responsive websites. Assisted in graphic designing.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams, including UI-UXdesigners and back-end developers to implement
  efficient and visually appealing user interfaces.

#### **PROJECTS WORKED**

**Business / Informative Websites, Landing Pages** | HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js, Bootstrap, jQuery, Python, and PHP.

- Clearly define the purpose of the website and align it with the business goals.
- Developed a mobile-first approach with media queries for optimal viewing on various devices.
- Implemented SEO best practices such as meta tags, keyword, and sitemap submission to enhance the website's visibility on search engines.

# E- Commerce Website | HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, jQuery.

- · Employed to create a responsive and flexible layout, enhancing the website's accessibility and usability.
- Ensured cross-browser compatibility and optimized performance for faster load times.

## **LANGUAGES**

English (Professional) | Malayalam (Fluent) | Hindi (Beginner Level) | Arabic (Read and Write).

## **DECLARATION**

I hereby declare that all the information furnished above are true and correct to the best of my knowledge.

#### SHAHEEN AHAMMED